Guide to the Time Inc. Corporate Administration Records 1853-2002 (bulk, 1929-1995) MS 3009-RG 5
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Corporate Strategy Files, 1976-2002 (bulk, 1979-1990); 10.92 Linear feet in 12 record cartons
  - Subseries V.A. Executive Vice President of Strategy and Development Gerald Levin Files, 1976-2002 (bulk, 1979-1990); 7.92 Linear feet in 9 record cartons
    Gerald "Jerry" Levin joined Time Inc. in 1972 as vice president of programming for Home Box Office (HBO) while the new subsidiary was still in development. He became president and chief executive officer (CEO) of HBO in March 1973 and then chairman of HBO in May 1976. In August of 1979, Time Inc. appointed Levin as the group vice president of video, overseeing Time-Life Films and HBO along with other cable operations and interests including American Television and Communications Corporation (ATC). In March 1984 Levin was named an executive vice president of Time Inc. making him the chief strategist. In July 1988 the Time Inc. board of directors elected him as a member and named him vice chairman of Time Inc. In this role Levin pursued alternative strategies for all areas of the company. During his time as vice chairman, he was one of the executives managing the merger between Time Inc. and Warner Communications, Inc. that created Time Warner. After the merger, he retained his vice chairman title.
    In January 1991, the board elected him as chairman of Time Warner. A few months later, the board named him chief operating officer handling media and entertainment business operations. In February 1992 Levin joined Steven J. Ross as co-CEO of Time Warner and replaced N. J. Nicholas, Jr. as president. Upon Ross's death in December of that year, Levin became the sole CEO. AT that time he reorganized the board to have fewer "insiders" or those employed by Time Warner as well as decreasing the overall number of members. By January 1993, the board elected Levin as chairman; he retained his titles as CEO and president.
    Under Levin's leadership, Time Warner and America Online (AOL) announced a merger (which was really an acquisition of Time Warner by AOL) in early 2000. The deal was made right before the internet stock bubble burst. This ended up being a difficult merger resulting in falling stock value and extensive cost cutting the new AOL Time Warner company. By October 2003, the company returned to its former name of Time Warner. Levin announced his retirement from Time Warner in December 2001 and left the company in May 2002.
    The majority of Gerald Levin's files date from his role as executive vice president (EVP) of strategy and development at the corporate level and vice chairman of Time Inc. overseeing strategy. His files were stored in the Time Inc. Archives as "corporate strategy" and include a mix of files from his time as HBO chairman, group vice president of video, EVP of strategy, and vice chairman of Time Inc. through the Time Inc. and Warner Communications merger. As they were found in the archives intermingled, they remain that way. The majority of Levin's files from his earlier roles with Video Group are in the Time Inc. Video Group Records (MS 3009-RG 41).
    The Administrative Files and Confidential Files of Levin's records document his work on defining the corporate mission; company restructuring; possible partnerships or ventures with other companies, including internationally; and his work on the Time Inc. and Warner communications merger. Records include correspondence with other companies; interoffice memoranda; presentations to the Board; notes on meetings for the Board, analysts, the Time Inc. annual meeting, and various conferences and company retreats; budgets; research on media industries; and transcripts and background information of speeches.
    The series Confidential Files retains the name the files had while in the Time Inc. Archives storage, but does not indicate restrictions. While there is no material difference from the Administrative Files, the Confidential Files remain in a separate series to document the division his office made during the transfer. Confidential Files are Levin's files on Time Inc.'s mergers and considered mergers with other companies, mainly the Time Warner merger. Some documents and original folder titles used code names for various companies such as "Gulf" for Gannett, "Tango" for Time Inc., and "Wonder" for Warner Communications. The use of "Gulf" for Gannett does not appear to have any relation to his files reviewing the possible acquisition of Gulf and Western Industries. Materials found inside the file titled "ABC-CBS" include notes on discussions with Warren Buffett and Berkshire Hathaway.
    Organized into two subsubseries: Subsubseries V.A.1.a. Administrative Files; and Subsubseries V.A.1.b. Confidential Files.
    - Subsubseries V.A.1. Administrative Files, 1976-2002 (bulk, 1979-1990); 4.67 Linear feet in 6 record cartons
      - Archival transfer form, 2002 (Offsite-box 791, Folder 1)
      - American Television and Communications Corporation strategy: 5 year plan: 1984-1988, 1983 (Offsite-box 791, Folder 2)
      - Analysts meeting: March 7, 1984 (Offsite-box 791, Folder 3)
      - Annual shareholders meeting: April 7, 1980 (Offsite-box 791, Folder 4)
      - Annual meeting, 1998 (Offsite-box 791, Folder 5)
      - Board meeting: Lyford Cay, Nassau, 1978 (Offsite-box 791, Folder 6)
      - Board meeting: Wyoming, 1981 (Offsite-box 791, Folder 7a)
      - Board update, 1987 March (Offsite-box 791, Folder 7b)
      - Books Group: Meeting, 1988 (Offsite-box 791, Folder 8)
      - Books Group: Planning conference, 1985 (Offsite-box 791, Folder 9)
      - Books study group, 1984 (Offsite-box 791, Folder 10-12)
      - Broadcast television industry report, 1985 (Offsite-box 791, Folder 13)
      - Budget: 1984-1988 (Offsite-box 791, Folder 14-18)
      - Budget: 1989-1990 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 1-2)
      - Business luncheon: Los Angeles, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 3)
      - Corporate conference: Lyford Cay, 1989 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 4)
      - Corporate mission, 1983-1986 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 5-6)
      - Corporate Strategy Group: "Discussion of Corporate Strategy", 1985 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 7)
      - Covidea: Presentation to the management committee, 1986 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 8)
      - Cunningham, Emory: Retirement, 1988 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 9)
      - Finance conference: Castle Harbour, Bermuda, 1989 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 10)
      - Financial presentation, 1984 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 11)
      - Financial presentation, 1987 April 3 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 12)
      - Goals, 1987 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 13)
      - Home Box Office (HBO) strategy: 5 year plan: 1984-1888, 1984-1986 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 14)
      - Human Resources conference, 1985 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 15)
      - Human Resources conference [binder cover], 1985 (Offsite-box 3807, Folder 6)
      - Japan partnerships: General, 1990-1991 (Offsite-box 793, Folder 1-2)
      - Japan partnerships: C. Itoh & Co. (Itochu), 1990 (Offsite-box 793, Folder 3-4)
      - Japan partnerships: Media International Corporation, 1990 (Offsite-box 793, Folder 5)
      - Japan partnerships: NHK Enterprises, Inc., 1990 (Offsite-box 793, Folder 6)
      - Japan partnerships: Toshiba, 1990-1991 (Offsite-box 793, Folder 7-9)
      - Little Brown: Arthur Thornhill dinner: May 27, 1987 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 16)
      - Magazine financial conference, 1988 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 17)
      - Magazine plans, 1985 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 18)
      - Management Meeting: Wyandanch Club, 1984 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 19)
      - Management Meeting: Wyandanch Club, 1985 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 20)
      - Motion picture industry reports, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 792, Folder 21-24)
      - Motion picture industry reports, 1984 (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 1)
      - Newstour, 1985 (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 2-3)
      - Pioneer Press, 1984 (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 4)
      - Presentation: Levin, 1977? (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 5)
      - Presentation: Levin: Video, 1977 (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 6)
      - Presentation: Levin: Home Box Office (HBO), 1978 (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 7)
      - Presentation: Levin: Financial analysts, 1979 (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 8)
      - Presentation: Munro, Richard, 1985 December 10 (Offsite-box 4255, Item 1)
      - Presentation: Munro, Richard, 1986 February (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 9-10)
      - Presentation: Munro, Richard, 1985 February (Offsite-box 4255, Item 2)
      - Presentation: The New Time Inc., 1983? (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 11)
      - Presentation: Time Inc. Board, 1985 April (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 12)
      - Reagan, Ronald: Eureka College, 1984 February 6 (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 13)
      - Restructuring, 1988 (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 14)
      - Rizzoli Group, 1990 (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 15)
      - Scott, Foresman & Company, 1987 (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 16)
      - Speeches: Levin: General, 1993 July-December (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 17)
      - Speech: Levin: American Marketing Association conference, 1982 (Offsite-box 4255, Folder 18)
      - Speech: Levin: Association of National Advertisers, 1981 November (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 1)
      - Speech: Levin: University of Georgia, 1978 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 2)
      - Speeches: Ross, Steven J., 1990-1991 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 3)
      - Stanley, Robert H.: Broadcasting and Home Box Office (HBO), 1976 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 4)
      - Sterling Forest retreat and project, 1976 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 5)
      - Stolley, Dick: Director of Special Projects, 1987 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 6)
      - Strategy, 1982, 1988 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 7-8)
      - Strategy Group report on strategy meeting, 1988 May (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 9)
      - Teletext Viewdata, 1981-1983 (Offsite-box 4256, Drawer 10-11)
      - Temple-Eastex: General, 1979 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 12)
      - Temple-Eastex: Board meeting: March 24-25, 1983 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 13-14)
      - Temple-Eastex: Board meeting: August 11, 1983 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 15)
      - Ten year financial plan, 1986 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 16)
      - Time Inc. vs. Ariel Sharon, 1985 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 17)
      - Time to Read program, 1986 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 18)
      - Time-Warner merger, 1989-1990 (Offsite-box 4256, Folder 19-20)
      - University of Pennsylvania: Institute for Law and Economics, 1985 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 1)
      - Video Group: Strategy and management meeting, 1983 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 2-3)
      - Video technology update, 1979 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 4-5)
      - Warner Amex: General, 1985 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 6)
      - Warner Amex: Descriptive memorandum, 1985 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 7)
      - Warner Amex: Descriptive memorandum [binder cover] (Offsite-box 3807, Folder 7)
      - Warner Communications, Inc., 1989 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 8)
    - Subsubseries V.A.2. Confidential Files, 1984-1990; 3.25 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
      - ABC-CBS, 1984 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 9)
      - CBS annual report, 1985 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 10)
      - Corporate strategy: General, 1988-1989 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 11-12)
      - Corporate strategy: Discussion, 1988 June (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 13)
      - Corporate strategy: Discussion [binder cover], 1988 June (Offsite-box 3807, Folder 8)
      - Financials, 1990 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 14)
      - Gannett Company: General, 1985 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 15-17)
      - Gannett Company / Allen Neuharth: Chronology of clips/articles: 1963-1985 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 18)
      - Gannett Company: Prototypes of publications, 1985-1986 (Offsite-box 4257, Folder 19)
      - Gannett Company: Project Gulf, 1985 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 1)
      - Gulf and Western Industries, 1985 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 2-3)
      - Gulf and Western Industries [RESTRICTED], 1985 (Offsite-box R16)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: General, 1988-1989 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 4-6)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: BHC Communications, inc., 1989 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 7)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Board: Letter to, 1989 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 8)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Board meeting, 1989 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 9)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Cash flow, 1988 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 10)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Certificate of Merger / Paramount v. Time, 1990 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 11)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Cris-Craft and BHC v. Warner, 1988 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 12)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Deposition [RESTRICTED], 1989 June 22-23 (Offsite-box R16)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Employment agreement [RESTRICTED], 1989 (Offsite-box R16)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Exchange ratio and compensation, 1988 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 13)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Exchange ratio and compensation [RESTRICTED], 1988 (Offsite-box R16)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Filmed entertainment, 1988 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 14)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Financials, 1988-1989 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 15-17)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Information packets, 1989 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 18)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Joint venture agreement [RESTRICTED], 1988 (Offsite-box R16)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Memoranda: General, 1987 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 19)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Memorandum: Merger update, 1989 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 20)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Merger agreement [RESTRICTED], 1988 (Offsite-box R16)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: News and notes, 1987 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 21)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Nicholas, N. J., undated (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 22)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Notes, 1987-1989 (Offsite-box 4258, Folder 23-25)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Notes, undated (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 1)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Plan of succession / Statement of principles, 1989 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 2)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Presentation script and slides, 1989? (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 3-4)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Press release, 1987 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 5)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Pro forma balance sheet and notes, 1988 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 6)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Public Affairs Conference II, 1985 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 7-8)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Purchase scenarios, 1988 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 9)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Ross, Steven J.: Compensation, 1988 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 10)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Securities and Exchange Commission filings: Time Inc. (Tango), 1988 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 11)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Securities and Exchange Commission filings: Warner Communications, Inc., 1987 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 12-13)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Stock options, 1989 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 14)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Summary timetable, 1988 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 15)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Tax meeting, 1988 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 16)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Time Inc. (Tango): Analysis of acquisition alternatives, 1988 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 17)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Time Inc. Magazine Group, 1988 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 18)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Warner Communications (Wonder): Information provided, 1989 (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 19-20)
      - Warner Communications, Inc. merger: Warner Communications (Wonder): Summary, undated (Offsite-box 4259, Folder 21)
  - Subseries V.B. Vice President of Strategy Development N. J. Nicholas, Jr. Files, 1981-1983; 0.5 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    N. J. Nicholas, Jr.'s files are a collection of reports and presentations from a short time period of corporate strategizing conducted by the Strategy Committee which looks like it was led by Nicholas and Bruce Hiland. These files were behind a tab labeled "Chapter I material." Some files in Winston Cox's files were behind a "Chapter Two" tab. It can be assumed those files are a continuation of the strategy begun with Nicholas's files. Nicholas's files were found in the same box with some of Cox's.
    Organized chronologically based on reversing the original loose reverse chronological arrangement.
    - Corporate Strategy: Introduction, 1981 August (Offsite-box 4260, Folder 1)
    - Strategy development, 1981 October (Offsite-box 4260, Folder 2)
    - Corporate strategy: Audit, 1981 September-November (Offsite-box 4260, Folder 3-5)
    - Corporate strategy: New objectives and strategies, 1982 March (Offsite-box 4260, Folder 6)
    - Strategic planning: Ultimate goal, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 4260, Folder 7)
  - Subseries V.C. Vice President of Corporate Strategy Winston Cox Files, 1984-1986; 1 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
    Winston "Tony" Cox's files document his work defining the corporate mission, company restructuring, and presenting on the corporate strategy to the Time Inc. board and other executives in the company. His records also contain files developing presentations and speeches regarding company strategy for Time Inc. President J. Richard Munro. While only two files refer to "Chapter Two," Cox's files overall may be a continuation of the work by N. J. Nicholas, Jr. whose files were behind a tab labeled "Chapter I."
    - Corporate retreat: Lyford Cay, 1985 (Offsite-box 4260, Folder 8-9)
    - Corporate strategy retreat: Wydandanch, 1984 October (Offsite-box 4260, Folder 10)
    - Corporate strategy retreat: Wydandanch, 1985 (Offsite-box 4260, Folder 11-12)
    - Executive briefing dinners, 1986 (Offsite-box 4260, Folder 13)
    - Munro, J. Richard: Leadership / Internal communications campaign, 1986 (Offsite-box 4260, Folder 14)
    - Munro, J. Richard: Mission / Strategy presentation to Management Group, 1985 (Offsite-box 4260, Folder 15)
    - Munro, J. Richard: Mission / Strategy presentation, 1986 (Offsite-box 4260, Folder 16-18)
    - Munro, J. Richard: Strategy and leadership presentations to Management Group, 1986 (Offsite-box 604, Folder 6)
    - Presentation: Finance Committee on financial capacity, 1986 October (Offsite-box 604, Folder 7)
    - Presentation: Strategy: To Board, 1986 (Offsite-box 604, Folder 8-9)
    - Stock repurchase, 1986 (Offsite-box 604, Folder 10)
    - Strategy: Chapter Two notes, 1985 (Offsite-box 604, Folder 11-12)
    - Strategy: Poison Pill: American Television and Communications Corporation stock sale, 1986 (Offsite-box 604, Folder 13)
    - Strategy and planning, 1984 (Offsite-box 604, Folder 14)
  - Subseries V.D. Corporate strategy studies and reports, 1984-1987; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
    Corporate strategy studies and reports contains bound booklets, with some accompanying correspondence, memoranda, or notes, on various industries of interest to Time Inc. Copies of studies and reports come from Executive Vice President of Strategy and Development Gerald Levin; Vice President of Corporate Strategy Winston "Tony" Cox; and Vice Presidents of Corporate Development Terri Hershey and Michael McCrudden.
    Areas of business include television programming rights and the industries of broadcasting, newspaper, books, home video and motion pictures. The records include files from the Business Information Task Force, general corporate strategy discussion, and updates to Time Inc.'s board. A few reports found with unfiled material in a box of Levin's files were moved to this record group by the archivist.
    - Motion picture industry, 1984 July (Offsite-box 4261, Folder 1)
    - Motion picture industry, 1984 (Offsite-box 4261, Folder 2-4)
    - Book industry, 1984 September (Offsite-box 4261, Folder 5-7)
    - Television industry: Syndication strategy, 1984 October (Offsite-box 4261, Folder 8)
    - Home video, 1984 November (Offsite-box 4261, Folder 9)
    - Business Information task force, 1984 December (Offsite-box 4261, Folder 10)
    - Corporate strategy discussion, 1985 March (Offsite-box 4261, Folder 11-12)
    - Broadcasting industry, 1985 June (Offsite-box 4261, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper industry, 1985 July (Offsite-box 4262, Folder 1-2)
    - Broadcasting industry, 1985 July (Offsite-box 4262, Folder 3)
    - Television programming, 1985 September (Offsite-box 4262, Folder 4-5)
    - Program rights, 1987 January (Offsite-box 4262, Folder 6-8)
      Includes digital material:
      1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "Computer Model. Motion Picture Ind. Base Case. October, 1986. McKinsey & Company."
      1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "Computer Model. Television Prog. Ind. Base Case. October, 1986. McKinsey & Company."
      1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "Computer Model. Representative Studio Ind. Base Case. October, 1986. McKinsey & Company."
    - Motion picture and broadcast, 1987 (Offsite-box 4262, Folder 9)
- Series VI. Executive Vice President Kelso Sutton Files, 1968-1994; 53 Linear feet in 53 record cartons
  Kelso Sutton worked at Time Inc. from 1961 to 1994 and held a variety of positions throughout his thirty-three year career. He joined the company as part of a management training program after graduating from Harvard University and began working in the Time circulation department. He subsequently became assistant business manager of Time in 1962, business manager in 1964 and general manager in 1968. In 1972, he was appointed director of the newly centralized corporate circulation department and elected as a company Vice President. He served as temporary acting editor of the Magazine Development Group for six months in 1976, after which he was appointed vice president of magazines for the Magazine Group. From 1978 to 1980, he was the publisher of Sports Illustrated.
  Sutton returned to the Magazine Group as the group vice president (1980-1984), executive vice president (1984-1985), and finally president and chief executive officer (CEO) (1985-1986). He was also elected to the board of directors of Time Inc. in 1983 and remained a member until his retirement. In December 1986, Sutton exchanged jobs with Reginald Brack and became president and CEO of the Book Group, which signaled a shift away from his previously powerful role within the company. He served in this role until the position was eliminated in 1993 after restructuring within Time Warner. Sutton then served as executive vice president for Time Inc. until his retirement in 1994.
  "Biography. Kelso F. Sutton. Group Vice President, Magazines, Time Inc." Time Inc. Public Affairs, January 1982.
  "Faces: Kelso Sutton, Group V.P. – Magazines. Time Inc." Folio, June 1981.
  Tyehimba, Cheo. "Sayonara, Sutton." F.Y.I., April 6, 1994.
  Kelso Sutton's files span approximately 1968 to 1994 and originated from his various roles within the Time Inc. Magazine Group (circa 1976-1986), his time as president and CEO of the Book Group (1986-1993), and his corporate-level work as a Time Inc. executive officer while member of the board of directors (circa 1983-1993) and finally as executive vice president (1993-1994). Because there is some overlap with these four groups, especially for strategic planning files, presentations, and speeches, all of his files were kept together in a single series.